34, Jalan Nuri 14 Bandar Puchong Jaya 47100 Puchong Selangor Darul Ehsan Malaysia

Tel No: 6-03-80701307 (Home) H/Phone No: 6-013-3421294 geraldcom@yahoo.com Skype Address: gerald.xmen



## **Personal Particulars**

I/C No. : 691005-10-5713 Passport No. : A16628660 Date of Birth : 5<sup>th</sup> October 1969

Race : Indian
Religion : Christian
Marital Status : Married

# **Professional Objective**

A Challenging and rewarding career advancement in the Quality & Telecommunication Industry.

# **Summary**

Over 20 years of leadership experience and increasing responsibility in the telecommunications industry including: directing, training, evaluating, coaching and operations planning. Extensive experience in implementing TL9000, ISO9001 and ISO14001 Quality Standards. Strong management skills in Quality Assurance, Operations Support, Inventory Control and Equipment Control.

# **Experience**

## 1. TELMAR NETWORK TECHNOLOGY – A JABIL COMPANY

**Background:** Telmar Network Technology (Subsidiary of Jabil Circuits) is a market leading provider of communications products and services to OEMs, enterprise and network service providers worldwide. Headquartered in Plano, Texas, Telmar has over 800 employees in 14 countries around the world. www.telmarnt.com

Position held: Quality Manager 2009 - 2013 Repair Manager 2008 - 2009

- Development and maintenance of Integrated Management System in accordance with the quality demands of TL9000, ISO 9001 & ISO14001.
- Promote quality achievement and performance improvement throughout the organization.
- Setting QA compliance objectives and ensuring that targets are achieved.
- Liaising with auditors and ensuring the execution of corrective action and compliance with present standard.
- Ensure compliance with national and international standards and legislation.
- Setting up and maintaining controls and documentation procedures.

## Page 2

- Develop & manage in-house repair processes, operations and capabilities.
- Implement stringent test procedures in order to reduce RMA.
- Build & manage repair tracking and inventory support.

#### 2. SEL TELECOMMUNICATIONS SDN. BHD.

**Background:** SEL Telecommunications Sdn Bhd is a local subsidiary of Alcatel SEL AG, Germany, which was formed in 1992. It has 25 employees at present where most of them were transferred from Alcatel SEL AG to SEL Telecommunications. SEL provides Engineering Services for the supply of Microwave Radio Transmission Systems and Mobile Network Systems and repair of such equipment in Malaysia. seltelecom.com.my

Positions held:	Repair Centre Supervisor	2004 - 2007
	Service & Maintenance Engineer	2002 - 2003
	Junior Service & Maintenance Engineer	2000 – 2001
	Senior Technical Assistant	1996 – 2000

- Troubleshooting of telecommunication equipment in the Repair Centre.
- Repair work done on Fibre Optics, ADM, SDH/PDH, BTS, Power Supply & Test Gears.
- Source and purchase of electronic components through the internet, local vendors etc.
- Field experience Frequency Survey, Testing, Commissioning & Trouble Shooting.
- Administration of repaired equipment, spare parts, overseas & local repairs.
- Development and maintenance of integrated system of operation management in accordance with the quality demands of ISO 9001 and ISO14001.

## 3. ALCATEL SEL AG, Germany

**Background:** Alcatel SEL AG, Germany, which is located in Malaysia was formed in 1986 and had about 105 employees at the beginning of its era. Alcatel was awarded the Telekom Malaysia Turnkey Project in 1988. In 1994 most of the employees were retrenched and some were transferred to SEL Telecommunications Sdn Bhd due to the end of the Turnkey Project and also other contracts. Alcatel was responsible for providing Engineering Services for the supply of Microwave Radio Transmission Systems and Mobile Network Systems and repair of such equipment in Malaysia. <a href="mailto:seltelecom.com.my">seltelecom.com.my</a>

## Position held: Technical Assistant 1992 – 1995

- Assist in the repair work in the Repair Centre.
- Calibration of Microwave equipment in the Repair Centre.
- Assist the Test and Commissioning Manager in providing data, Test Gears, Microwave equipment to the field engineers.
- Problem solving through the phone on commissioning of links and troubleshoot problems in the field.

On 1<sup>st</sup> January 1994, Alcatel SEL AG, Germany decided to transfer all its staff to our local subsidiary, SEL Telecommunications Sdn Bhd which provides Engineering Services for the supply of Microwave Radio Transmission Systems and Mobile Network Systems and repair of such equipment in Malaysia.

Page 3

#### 4. PAN EQUALIZERS TELECOMMUNICATIONS

**Background:** Pan Equalizers' core business was marketing the ATUR 450 Mobile phone and UPS Power Supply for computers. It also provided technical support for their customers in Malaysia. It had about 70 employees.

Position held: Technician 1991 – 1992

- Assist the Technical Executive in conducting component level service, repair and calibrations for ATUR 450 and ART 900 mobile telephone.
- Administration of the Service Centre.

## 5. **TELEDYNAMICS (M) SDN. BHD.**

**Background:** Teledynamics core business was marketing office automation products. The company provided technical support for its customers in Malaysia. It employed about 300 staff. www.teledynamics.com.my

Position held: Technician – Keyphone and Facsimile Division 1990 – 1991

- Install, commission, service and maintain the above mentioned equipment.
- Attend to corporate clients.
- Conduct on the job training for junior technicians.
- Supervise in planning and implementation of calls.

#### Education

Southern Pacific University (USA) Bachelor of Science in Electrical & Electronics Engineering www.spuni.edu	2005-2006
Systematic College NCC International Diploma in Computer Studies www.systematic.edu.my	1995-1996
Industrial Training Institute	
Sijil Juruteknik Perindustrian-Industrial Electronics	1988-1989
(Industrial Technician's Certificate)	
Sijil Kecekapan Ketukangan-MLVK Intermediate in Industrial Electronics	1989
(Craftsmanship Competency Certificate)	
Sijil Kecekapan Ketukangan-MLVK Basic in Industrial Electronics	1988
(Craftsmanship Competency Certificate)	
<u>www.ilpkl.gov.my</u>	

Sekolah Menengah Taman SEA (Taman SEA Secondary School)

## Page 4

1986

2002

2000

2000

ii. Examination: Sijil Rendah Pelajaran (Lower Education Certificate) Results: Pangkat A (Grade A)  Training  Lean Leadership & Change Management Training Oracle SCM (Supply Chain Management) Function Transition to ISO 9001:2008 Standard TL9000 Release 4.0 Requirements (QuEST Forum) Understanding TL9000 QMS for Telecommunication Products & Services Being Successful as a Supervisor & Team Leader Quality Management System (QMS) MS ISO 9001:2000 and Internal Quality Audit HP Scalar Network Analyzer DMC XP-4 Mini Link  1984  2013 2013 2014 2015 2015 2016 2017 2017 2018 2018 2019 2019 2019 2019 2019 2019 2019 2019	i.	Examination: Results:	Sijil Pelajaran Malaysia (Malaysian Education Certificate) 3 <sup>rd</sup> Grade	
<ul> <li>Lean Leadership &amp; Change Management Training</li> <li>Oracle SCM (Supply Chain Management) Function</li> <li>Transition to ISO 9001:2008 Standard</li> <li>TL9000 Release 4.0 Requirements (QuEST Forum)</li> <li>Understanding TL9000 QMS for Telecommunication Products &amp; Services</li> <li>Being Successful as a Supervisor &amp; Team Leader</li> <li>Quality Management System (QMS) MS ISO 9001:2000 and Internal Quality Audit</li> <li>HP Scalar Network Analyzer</li> </ul>	ii.	Results:		1984
<ul> <li>Oracle SCM (Supply Chain Management) Function</li> <li>Transition to ISO 9001:2008 Standard</li> <li>TL9000 Release 4.0 Requirements (QuEST Forum)</li> <li>Understanding TL9000 QMS for Telecommunication Products &amp; Services</li> <li>Being Successful as a Supervisor &amp; Team Leader</li> <li>Quality Management System (QMS) MS ISO 9001:2000 and Internal Quality Audit</li> <li>HP Scalar Network Analyzer</li> </ul>			Training	
<ul> <li>Transition to ISO 9001:2008 Standard</li> <li>TL9000 Release 4.0 Requirements (QuEST Forum)</li> <li>Understanding TL9000 QMS for Telecommunication Products &amp; Services</li> <li>Being Successful as a Supervisor &amp; Team Leader</li> <li>Quality Management System (QMS) MS ISO 9001:2000 and Internal Quality Audit</li> <li>HP Scalar Network Analyzer</li> </ul>	•	Lean Leadersh	nip & Change Management Training	2013
<ul> <li>TL9000 Release 4.0 Requirements (QuEST Forum)</li> <li>Understanding TL9000 QMS for Telecommunication Products &amp; Services</li> <li>Being Successful as a Supervisor &amp; Team Leader</li> <li>Quality Management System (QMS) MS ISO 9001:2000 and Internal Quality Audit</li> <li>HP Scalar Network Analyzer</li> </ul>	•	·		
<ul> <li>Understanding TL9000 QMS for Telecommunication Products &amp; Services</li> <li>Being Successful as a Supervisor &amp; Team Leader</li> <li>Quality Management System (QMS) MS ISO 9001:2000 and Internal Quality Audit</li> <li>HP Scalar Network Analyzer</li> </ul>	•	· 11 • ,		
<ul> <li>Being Successful as a Supervisor &amp; Team Leader</li> <li>Quality Management System (QMS) MS ISO 9001:2000 and Internal Quality Audit</li> <li>HP Scalar Network Analyzer</li> </ul>	•	TL9000 Release 4.0 Requirements (QuEST Forum)		
<ul> <li>Quality Management System (QMS) MS ISO 9001:2000 and Internal Quality Audit</li> <li>HP Scalar Network Analyzer</li> </ul>	•	• • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •		
Internal Quality Audit 2005  HP Scalar Network Analyzer 2005	•	Being Successful as a Supervisor & Team Leader		
HP Scalar Network Analyzer     2005	•	Quality Manag	gement System (QMS) MS ISO 9001:2000 and	
,		Internal Qualit	y Audit	2005
DMC XP-4 Mini Link     2003	•	HP Scalar Network Analyzer		
	•	DMC XP-4 Mir	ni Link	2003

## **Professional Skills**

- Computer skills Proficient in Microsoft Outlook, Word, Excel, Power-Point.
- Excellent communications skills with staff, management & customers

Workshop in Internal Quality Auditing (ISO 9001:2000)

- Able to quickly adapt to new situations
- Able to perform multi-tasking

Alcatel BTS Equipment

SDH ADM Equipment

During my tenure in the telecommunications field, I have handled various types of wireless equipments such as Racal: BTS Tester, Scalar Network Analyzers, Spectrum Analyzers, Data Transmission Analyzers, Protocol Analyzers, Frequency Scanners, Power Meters, DMC PDH wireless equipment, Optical Systems, BTS, ADM, SDH and PDH Alcatel equipment and various parabolic antennas, VSWR equipment, wave guides and various transmission equipment.

**Equipment Experience** – Alcatel SDH 9600- 2MB - 34MB - 140MB, PDH 9400UX (Melody), Ericsson Mini Link, Marconi SDH 155E, Siemens SRAL, Motorola HM6, Siemens BS240, Ericsson RBS2106, Nortel S8000, Nokia Intratalk, Harris Stratex, Nokia Flexihopper and Scada System.

Page 5

## **Software**

Windows XP, Microsoft Office 98 & 2000, Windows 2000NT, Autocad, Nectas, Alcatel Lux 10-40, DMC Link-View.

# Languages

- Excellent written English and Malay Language
- Excellent spoken English and Malay Language
- Good spoken Tamil Language

## References

i. Name : Mr. Paramesvaran Visuvanathan

Position : Project Manager

Company's Name : Telmar Network Technology

Tel. No. (Office) : 603-56355611 H/Phone No. : 6-012-3881919

Email Address : <u>Paramesvaran.Visuvanathan@telmarnt.com</u>,

my rames@yahoo.com

ii. Name : Mr. P. Kukan

Position : Operations and Repair Centre Manager Company's Name : SEL Telecommunications Sdn Bhd

Tel No. (Office) : 603-51226016 (Ext: 112)

H/Phone No. : 6-012-548 5854, 6-018-2005858

Email Address : <u>pkukan58@yahoo.com</u>